黑 鏡
可以開始了
They're ready now.
請你從去年五月的事件開始
Perhaps we could begin with your earliest recollections
進行陳述
of the events of last May.
我是5月15日開始調查這個案子的
Well, I first got involved on the 15th.
能請你把話筒挪近些嗎
Could you move the microphone a little closer?
夠近了嗎
Here?
我是5月15日開始調查這個案子的
I first got involved on the 15th.
全網公敵
5月15日
第一天
字幕組
僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
最新最快海外影視字幕下載
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
翻譯：章魚埃克斯 澈塵 鹽湖涼開水 瀟然
翻譯：桃小兔吃冰棒 杏仁斯嘉麗 小酸奶!
翻譯： showeryhe 胡說大王
時間軸：倩倩 西查 Ans 林卡
后期：吉吉  校對/總監：草草
財相湯姆·皮克林出面解釋
Chancellor Tom Pickering has defended
政府就殘疾人津貼問題的政策立場
the government's stance on disability benefits
以回應輿論對于所謂
as outrage over the death of
"輪椅烈士"格溫·馬博里之死愈演愈烈的憤怒
so- called "Wheelchair Martyr" Gwen Marbury grows.
已有超過兩萬人簽署請愿書
More than 20,000 people have signed a petition
要求解雇報紙專欄作家喬·鮑爾斯
demanding the sacking of newspaper columnist Jo Powers
因為她發表了關于格溫·馬博里的爭議文章
following her controversial article about Gwen Marbury.
環保組織宣布又有一物種完全滅絕
Conservationists have announced another extinction.
由于白鶴種群賴以生存的
The Siberian crane has died out
濕地地貌空前萎縮  該物種已完全消失
following an unprecedented reduction in its wetland habitat.
而模擬蜜蜂的機器昆蟲人造蜂
And the honeybee-mimicking drone insects known as ADIs
今夏再次被激活
have been activated for their second summer.
希望你知道羞恥
Hope you're ashamed of yourself.
-婊子  -幸會
- Bitch. - Pleasure's all mine.
86條新消息提及了你
你是鮑爾斯
Yo Powers?
喬·鮑爾斯
Jo Powers.
那盒子里的東西會爆炸嗎
Whatever's in there, will it detonate?
是蛋糕房送來的  給你的
That's from bakery. For you.
-謝謝  -謝謝
- Thank you. - Thank you.
回來了  親愛的
Hello, darling!
好有創意  是你的"粉絲"送來的
Creative, your well-wishers.
臭婊子
你還有心吃
Don't eat it.
就是個蛋糕  就是給人吃的
It's a cake. That's its job.
我去洗個澡
I'm going to have a bath.
喬·鮑爾斯
眼光獨到  一往無前  勇敢直言
什么"烈士"  不用流淚
"輪椅烈士"格溫·馬博里被奉為英雄  喬·鮑爾斯則認為她的公開自殺代表了最糟糕的求關注
喬·鮑爾斯就是個人形垃圾
這寫的什么雞巴玩意  放尊重點好嗎  你早晚也得坐輪椅  喬·鮑爾斯
翻了翻格溫的書  至少她真的站出來反對這些預算裁減了
而不是只會亂噴  你個垃圾喬·鮑爾斯  不要臉  無恥
你個婊子  就沒點同情心嗎
你有200+條新消息
其中96條提到了你
賤逼婊子長什么樣  就長@作家喬·鮑爾斯 那樣
@作家喬·鮑爾斯 操你媽
讓人惡心的婊子
喬·鮑爾斯#去死
就是一婊子
格萊美獎得主  說唱歌手塔斯克做客本節目
Grammy Award winning rapper Tusk is still with us.
塔斯克  網上有超多人
Now, Tusk, there are loads of online videos
發了模仿你的視頻
of people trying to emulate you,
但我們最喜歡的是這個  來看一下
but this is our favourite. Take a look at this.
是個叫阿倫·希恩的小伙子
It's a young chap called Aaron Sheen.
今年九歲
He's nine years old.
這孩子看起來蠢死了
That is one goofy-looking kid.
跳得也不好
Not a good dancer.
他才九歲  拜托他已經跳得很好了
He's nine years old! Come on, he's a pretty good dancer.
這小逼崽子跳得什么破爛玩意
That young motherfucker can't dance for shit.
他趁早放棄學別的去吧
He should probably just give up now, actually.
別恨我對你說了真話
Don't hate on me for keeping it real.
就這一臉蠢樣的逼崽子能跳出花兒來才怪
That's a goofy little motherfucker, and he can't dance for shit.
他可是你的狂熱粉  塔斯克
He is a big fan, Tusk.
也別恨我說實話
Don't hate on your boy for keeping it real.
誰不是從零開始學起的
Everybody's got to start somewhere.
從零學起  我當初可比他跳得好多了
Start somewhere? I looked better than that- -
-帕克總督察  -不接受采訪
- DCI Parke? - No press.
不  我不是記者
No, I'm not press.
見習警官布藍·科爾森  是你的跟班
TDC Blue Colson. I'm your shadow.
我的跟班  他們說...
My shadow? They said...
抱歉  叫我卡琳吧
Sorry. Call me Karin.
-你剛才說你叫  -布藍
- Did you say your name was...? - Blue.
-藍色的那個藍  -對  不是外號
- B-l-u-e, Blue? - Yeah. It's not a nickname.
我爸喜歡這個字
My dad liked the sound of it.
-以前見過尸體嗎  -幾次吧
- Seen a body before? - A couple.
-不過是在視頻里  -老大
- On video, I mean. -  Boss?
這位是布藍  是我的跟班
This is Blue. She's my shadow.
-尼克·謝爾頓警長  -什么情況
- DS Nick Shelton. - What've we got?
喬·鮑爾斯
Jo Powers.
-就是那個  -就是那個喬·鮑爾斯
- As in... - As in actual Jo Powers.
我之前看過她寫的關于一個殘疾女的文章
Saw something she wrote the other day about the wheelchair woman.
引戰文章  專門惹人生氣的
Clickbait piece. Pissed people off.
那破文章簡直不可理喻  連我都簽了請愿書
That article was fucking horrendous. Even I signed the petition.
想砸她飯碗
To get her sacked.
走吧
Come on.
鄰居聽見她慘叫  就報警了
Neighbours heard her screaming and called it in.
好一番打斗啊
Hell of a struggle.
還有別人在家嗎
Anyone else at home?
她丈夫  肚子上被劃了一刀
Husband. Found slashed across the stomach.
-她劃的  -不清楚
- By her? - Don't know.
他還在昏迷中  送去圣哥倫布醫院了
He was unconscious. They've taken him to St. Columbus.
快看  警察封鎖了@作家喬·鮑爾斯 的家  他們不可能活捉她
據傳警察到了@作家喬·鮑爾斯 的家  希望他們為她的仇恨言論逮捕她
@她的消息還在瘋涌而來
Her mentions are still pouring in.
@作家喬·鮑爾斯 的文章真惡毒  快開除她
窗戶都拴上了
Restraining bolt's in place.
還有別的入口嗎
No other points of entry?
沒有  而且前門外裝了監控探頭
No. But the outside's ringed with CCTV.
攝像頭密碼拿到了嗎
We got the code for the cams?
那好  先檢查錄像
Okay, then. Check the recordings.
取樣送毒理科檢測
Bag that, send it to Toxicology.
給她做全面尸檢
Full autop for her,
等她丈夫醒了我們再訊問他
and we question the husband as soon as he wakes up.
走吧
Come on.
-你覺得是丈夫  -我覺得各種可能都有
- You think it's the husband? - I'm keeping options open.
割喉  這可不常見  辛苦了幾位
Cutting the throat, that's unusual. Thanks, chaps.
但你認為是他做的
But you do think he did it?
現在什么都不清楚
Don't know anything yet.
出了這種事  不是喝醉  吸毒就是吵架了
These things are almost always either drink, drugs or domestic.
八成就是這樣
It is how it is.
-你開車回家嗎  -沒駕照  沒考過
- You driving home? - No licence. Never passed.
我還在等無人駕駛普及呢
I'm sort of waiting for driverless to go mainstream.
-上車吧  -不用了  我去搭地鐵
- Get in. - No, honestly, I'll get the Tube.
上車
Get in.
好吧
Okay.
你之前在科技犯罪科
So you were in Tech Crime?
數據鑒證科  負責電腦技術
Digital Forensics. Computer murk.
那怎么走了  覺得無聊了嗎
What happened, you get bored of it?
也不是
Not exactly.
你也看過人們都在這玩意里藏了些什么
You've seen what people tuck away on these.
陰謀啊  殺人名單啊  兒童色情什么的
Schemes and kill lists, kiddy porn.
一點都不無聊
It's not boring.
我還記得年輕的時候
I'm old enough to remember
人們也是滿腦子想著這種事
when they walked around with that stuff
只不過都藏在腦子里
just tucked away in their heads.
是啊  不過現在他們
Right. But now they can't help
都把這些東西托付給這個小幫手
but entrusting it to their little companions.
這東西吸收了我們的人格
These things absorb who we are.
對我們無所不知
They know everything about us.
既然不是無聊  那為什么離開鑒證科
If it's interesting, why leave Forensics?
蘭諾赫案
The Rannoch case.
-伊安·蘭諾赫  -對  那個兒童殺手
- Ian Rannoch? - The child killings, yeah.
就是我破解了他的紀念品文件夾
I was the one who cracked his souvenir folder.
所以那些圖片你也看到了
So you saw those pictures?
還有視頻  全都看了
And the videos too. Saw them all.
那種東西  看一眼就能改變你
You see something like that, it changes you.
你要么就此崩潰  要么會想...
You either get defeated or you think...
你會想  "去他的  我得阻止這些人渣"
You think, "Fuck me! I've got to help stop that shit."
對
Yeah.
-在外勤工作  -什么外勤
- I mean, out here in the field...  - What fucking field?
你懂我的意思  就是在現實世界里
You know what I mean. Out here in the real world,
我們真的可以阻止壞事  對不對
you can genuinely prevent stuff, can't you?
你還太年輕
You are young.
也許是你太老
Maybe you're old?
小心哦
Steady.
多謝
Thanks.
-明天見  -好的  老大
- See you tomorrow. - Yes, boss.
喬·鮑爾斯被發現死于倫敦西區的家中
Jo Powers has been found dead at her home in West London.
專欄作家死亡
這位資深專欄作家近日身陷輿論漩渦
The veteran columnist had been at the centre of controversy
起因是她寫了一篇
over an article she'd written
關于殘疾人權益活動家格溫·馬博里的文章
about disability rights activist Gwen Marbury.
警方尚未查明死因
The police have yet to confirm the cause--
第二天
-這么早就開工  -我拜托尼克給我看監控
- Starting early? - I asked Nick to show me the CCTV.
-是嗎  -嗯
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
沒發現有人進出  整晚只有喬和她丈夫
No one came in or out. Just Jo and her husband all evening.
-那一個呢  -是后院的
- And that one there? - Rear patio.
看來已經壞了幾個月了
Bust for months by the looks of it.
可能有人從那里進去的
Someone could've come in through there.
那他們得翻柵欄進來  作案后再翻出去
They'd have to climb the fence, make it in and out,
而且事先知道攝像頭壞了
knowing the camera wasn't working,
不過的確是有可能  嚴格來講
but yeah, could have happened. Technically.
好  抱歉
Okay, sorry.
挺熱心啊你
You're keen to help.
家求我的
She just asked!
搜索
用戶名  @作家喬·鮑爾斯
關鍵詞  婊子  賤人
操  蕩婦  去死  殺
去死吧@作家喬·鮑爾斯
大家來請愿  立即開除@作家喬·鮑爾斯
要是@作家喬·鮑爾斯 死了  我會大笑
@作家喬·鮑爾斯 被火燒死吧
@作家喬·鮑爾斯 就是個該死的賤逼
是這樣
So...
我在搜集過去48小時內所有針對
I'm collating every threat or insult levelled at Jo Powers
喬·鮑爾斯的威脅和辱罵
over the previous 48 hours.
就算是丈夫  那也只是巧合吧
Say it is the husband. That's a coincidence, isn't it?
不見得  人人都問候你全家八輩
Not really. You've got everyone throwing a shit fit.
這兩口子承擔的壓力肯定爆表了
Stress levels in that household would've been through the roof.
這種網絡熱點和天氣一樣  熱一陣就過去了
That Internet stuff drifts off like weather.
就是嘴上噴噴  不是當真的
It's half hate. They don't mean it.
但是婚姻中的仇恨  那可是立體真實的
The hate in a marriage, that's in 3D.
是投入了心思的  是發自內心的
That's had work put into it. That's sincere.
怎么了  我離過婚
Yeah. I'm divorced.
丈夫醒了  開口說話了
Husband's up and talking.
你肯定喜歡他的不在場證詞
You're gonna love his alibi.
圣哥倫布醫院
我聽見喬在樓上慘叫
I heard Jo screaming from upstairs.
我跑進去后就看見她滿屋子亂跑亂撞
And when I ran in, she was walking 'round the room, stumbling.
她在抓什么
She was clutching...
她在撓她的頭  似乎她非常痛苦
She... was clutching her head as if she was in pain.
然后突然之間  她停下了
And then for a moment, she stopped.
就像抽搐了似的  她就那么
And then it was like a seizure, she was...
使勁抽
thrashing...
使勁撓自己
clawing at her own skin.
然后她就去
And she turned...
她就拿自己的頭
She smashed her head...
往桌子上使勁撞
onto the desk, hard.
然后  她推開我
Then she...  she pushed me over.
酒瓶子肯定就是在那時撞碎了
That must've been when the bottle smashed.
然后她撿起碎片  開始割自己
Then she picked it up, and she started cutting herself.
割這里  往這里鑿
Here. She was gouging.
我試著攔住她
I tried to stop her.
但是她捅了我
But she did this.
然后她就割了自己的喉嚨
Then she cut her throat.
我想阻止她
I tried to stop her.
她用碎玻璃割了自己的喉嚨
She cut her own throat with the glass!
自殘加自殺  卻沒有明顯的原因
Mutilated and then killed herself for no apparent reason?
要我說這不太可能
I'd say the odds are against that.
他說她好像在抽搐
He said it was like she was having a seizure.
也許是蛋糕里放了什么
Maybe there was something in the cake.
-蛋糕  -就是上面寫著"臭婊子"的那個
- The cake? - It had "Fucking bitch" iced on it.
-也許里面加了什么東西  -毒品嗎
- Could've been something in it. - Like a drug?
-我不知道  -讓人自殺的毒品
- I don't know. - That makes people kill themselves?
他說得有幾分可信
He was sort of convincing.
-他實在不像是那種  -別說什么這種那種
- He just doesn't seem the...  - Don't say "The type."
他是個正常人  就是這種人
He's ordinary. That is the type.
怎么  那是他拿她的頭撞桌子
What, so he bounced her head off the desk?
-布藍  -是他緊抓著她...
- Blue. - Held her steady enough--
-布藍  -怎么了
- Blue. - What?
-毒理科正在檢測蛋糕  -好吧
- Toxicology are looking at the cake. - Okay.
與此同時我們去拜訪下送蛋糕的人
Meantime, let's drop in on the person that sent it.
今早剛剛查到的
Got the name this morning.
-你不用哄著我  -這不是你想查的嗎
- You don't need to patronize me. - We're doing what you want.
-調查另一個線索  -但你認為是浪費時間
- Following another lead. - That you think is a waste of time.
大多數時候我們的工作就是去調查死胡同
Picking along dead ends just to prove they're dead ends,
好證明它們的確是死胡同
that's most of the job.
我沒說那是在浪費時間
I'm not saying it's a waste of time.
只是你還沒對現實感到厭倦
Just you haven't had a chance to get bored of reality yet.
好吧  我是在哄你
Okay, that was patronizing.
這是送蛋糕的那個人嗎
Is this who sent the cake?
莉莎·巴哈  女
-我們查過她的社交信息了嗎  -我不知道
- Have we checked her social feeds? - I don't know.
莉莎·巴哈  搜索
科爾比恩莊園  這是一所好學校
"喬·鮑爾斯去死"
"Death to Jo Powers."
莉莎·巴哈  @作家喬·鮑爾斯 #去死
她星期一早上發的
She posted that on Monday morning.
蛋糕店說他們不寫這種臟話
The bakery said that they're not meant to do obscenities,
所以我說那是給我妹妹的  開個玩笑而已
so I said it was for my sister, like just a joke thing,
他們就同意了
and they agreed, so...
他們家的蛋糕不便宜啊
Not cheap, their cakes.
加上外送費  有80英鎊吧
With delivery, it was what, 80 quid?
不全是我付的錢
Well, I didn't pay for it all myself.
-我們每個人出了一英鎊  -我們
- We all put a pound in each. - We?
對  我上一個媽媽和看護留言板
Yeah. I'm on a mums and carers message board.
我做了個募捐
I held a sort of whip-round.
-你眾籌的錢  -對  可以這么說
- You crowd-sourced the money? - Yeah, if you like.
有另外80個人捐錢
From 80 other people?
聽著  我沒有
Look, I'm not...
我沒有開玩笑  好嗎  我知道她死了
I'm not being funny, okay? I know she is dead.
但是你讀過她寫的文章嗎
But did you read what she had written?
你覺得她寫那種東西
How much do you think she got paid
掙了多少錢
for spouting that horrible shit?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只是使用了我言論自由權
I was just using my freedom of speech.
來發恐嚇信息
To send a threatening message.
聽著
Look.
那樣就是好玩  行嗎
It was funny, okay?
我明白如果是我一個人做的
And I can see if I'd done it myself,
是會有點奇怪
then that would be a bit weird,
但我不是瘋子
but I'm not mental.
你希望她死掉
You wished she was dead.
不  我沒有
No, no, I didn't.
"喬·鮑爾斯去死"
"Death to Jo Powers."
那只不過是...
That's just...
標簽游戲  比如"誰誰誰去死"
It's a-- a hashtag game, you know, like "Death to..."
你附上某個犯渾的人的名字
You insert the name of someone who's being an arsehole.
那不是認真的  就是個玩笑
It's not... real. It's a joke thing.
誰發起的那個標簽
And who started it? The hashtag?
我不知道  我就是在哪看到的
I don't know. I don't know. I saw it somewhere.
我們失陪下
Excuse us a moment.
毒理科說蛋糕沒問題
Toxicology say the cake's clean.
他們還說  "謝謝  蛋糕很美味"
They also said: "Thanks, it was delicious."
我們按照《攻擊言論法》給她個警告
We'll give her a caution. Offensive Communications Act.
-蛋糕上的話也算嗎  -就她而言  算
- Does that cover cakes? - As far as she's concerned, it does.
那其他捐了錢的人呢
What about the others who chipped in?
你也要去責備他們嗎
Are you going to tell them off, too?
-我什么都沒做  -去網上留言吧
- I didn't do anything. - Start a thread about it.
莉莎·巴哈  @作家喬·鮑爾斯 #去死
那個丈夫明天出院
Hospital's discharging the husband tomorrow.
我們會把他帶來訊問
We'll bring him in for questioning.
布藍  我們要逮捕那個丈夫
Blue? We're arresting the husband.
別再想了
Don't wallow in that.
網民今天就會換個對象發火
The Internet will be pissed off with someone else today.
塔斯克
Tusk.
所有人都在生塔斯克的氣
Everyone's pissed off with Tusk
因為他對那個孩子做的事
cause of that thing with the kid.
他在社交網絡上被炮轟了
He's catching a shit storm on social media.
塔斯克不當言論激怒互聯網
莉莎現在應該在組織訂蛋糕了
Liza will be organising the cake now.
-明天見  -再見
- See you tomorrow. - See you.
滾回家塔斯克  塔斯克#去死
毫無風度  過分  而且那孩子那么可愛@饒舌歌手塔斯克
利物浦阿波羅  塔斯克
我的美女都哪去了
Where my ladies at?
做得漂亮
You killed it, man.
是啊  表演不錯  兄弟
Yeah, that's a good show, brother.
-我超有感覺  -想來點這個嗎
- I'm feeling my shit. - You want some of that?
-你還吸這個  -好東西  哥們
- What you smoking? - Good shit, boy.
好吧
A'ight.
我去
Damn.
有監控  有監控
Eyes on, eyes on, eyes on.
別緊張  在這里是合法的
Don't stress. It's legal here.
我總是忘  歡迎來到歐洲
Keep forgetting. Welcome to Europe, I guess.
-還有點失去樂趣了  -這還用說
- Kinda takes the joy out of it. - Tell me about it.
小心點  摔壞了要你賠
Careful! You break it, you pay for it.
總是添亂
Always doing some bullshit.
塔斯克  塔斯克
Tusk? Tusk?
這里需要幫忙
We need some help over here!
-我在這兒呢  -讓它出去  讓它出去
- I got you. - Get it out! Get it out!
讓它出去
Get it out!
叫救護車
Call an ambulance!
開始
Commencing.
-他說是什么事了嗎  -沒有
- Did he say what it is? - Nope.
第三天
-早上好  -早
- Good morning. - Morning.
她在里面
She's in here.
我查看了大腦內部
So I go in,
不只有玻璃造成的創傷
and there's not just the wound from the glass.
有一個洞
There's a hole.
鉆出來的洞  像個小隧道一樣
Dug in. A bore hole, like a tiny tunnel.
所以我順著往里看  看它有多深
So I follow it, you know, how deep does it go?
從耳道一直到大腦深處
It goes all the way from her ear canal to deep in her brain.
然后我找到了這個
Where I find this.
就待在那里  看起來挺安逸的
Nestled right in there. Looks quite cosy.
-這是那種什么蜜蜂  -人造蜂
- It's one of those bee things. - An ADI.
顆粒計劃研制的自主昆蟲
An Autonomous Drone Insect from the Granular Project.
-它怎么進去的  -我認為是打洞進去的
- How did it get in there? - I'd say it burrowed in.
-操  -這還不是最糟糕的
- Fuck me. - That's not the worst part.
它正好爬到她的腦島背后側
It crawled right through her dorsal posterior insula,
也就是大腦的痛覺中樞
which is basically the brain's pain centre.
那是極度的痛苦
You're talking agony off the scale.
你會不惜一切地讓它停下
You'd do anything to make it stop.
甚至割自己的喉嚨
Even cut your own throat.
-下午好  -帕克總督察
- Good afternoon. - DCI Parke.
-見習警官布藍·科爾森  -謝謝
- TDC Blue Colson. - Okay. Thank you.
這些公司都太他媽華麗了
They're so fucking fancy-looking, these companies.
-用數十億打造品牌  -他們付得起
- Billions on branding. - Well, they can afford it.
整個人造蜂工程基本上是政府資助的
The whole ADI project's pretty much bankrolled by the government.
所以有那么多人對此很擔憂
It's why so many people are paranoid about it.
我猜猜  是互聯網上的一些人
Let me guess, this is some people on the Internet?
他們認為政府用這些蜜蜂監視我們
They reckon the government uses the bees to spy on us.
真是精神分裂的世界觀啊
There's a schizophrenic world view.
天啊
Jesus,
我從沒指望能活在未來
I didn't expect to find myself living in the future,
但是我現在就處在未來
but here I fucking well am.
卡琳·帕克
Karin Parke?
溫妮莎·達爾
Vanessa Dahl.
請跟我來
Please. Follow me.
你們想了解人造蜂群工程的信息嗎
You're after information on our Project Swarm ADIs?
沒錯
That's right.
有什么原因嗎
Any particular reason?
有
Yes.
拉斯姆斯
Rasmus.
拉斯姆斯·斯約博格
Rasmus Sjoberg.
他是蜂群工程的帶頭人
He heads Swarm.
很高興認識你們
Nice to meet you.
-不錯的溫室  -是啊
- Nice greenhouse. - Yeah.
那么  你的蜜蜂  人造蜂  跟我說說
So, your bees, your ADIs, talk me through them.
蜂群崩壞綜合癥  我們仍然不了解背后的原因
Colony Collapse Disorder. We still don't know what's behind it.
蜜蜂差不多已經滅絕了
Bees themselves were virtually extinct so
所以我們的人造蜂相當于替代了它們
what our ADIs do is effectively stand in for them.
它們是太陽能驅動的  不用采蜜
They're solar powered. They don't need nectar.
但是它們同樣會給花傳粉
but they pollinate flowers the same way.
它們爬進去  花粉會粘在它們腿上
They crawl inside, pollen sticks to their legs
然后沾在下一朵花上
and gets brushed off the next flower they visit.
它們能產蜜嗎
Can they make honey?
不能
No.
我只是開玩笑
I was joking.
它們怎么知道花在哪
How do they know where the flowers even are? I mean...
它們有傳感器
Well, they have a sensor.
像是  攝像頭
Like a... camera?
不是  只是基礎的視覺傳感器
No. Just a basic visual sensor.
它們需要基本的模式識別系統
You see, they need rudimentary pattern recognition
才能定位相同的植物群并進行導航
in order to locate compatible flora and navigate.
-它們能導航  -是的
- They navigate? - Yes.
你不用
You don't... I don't know...
操控它們嗎
steer them?
它們是自主行動的  對吧
They're autonomous. That's right, isn't it?
它們自己做決定  自己照顧自己
They make their own decisions. They look after themselves.
對  人造蜂覆蓋整個英國
Yes. You see, the ADIs cover the whole of the UK.
我們不可能分別控制每只蜂
We couldn't command each one individually ourselves.
在邏輯上不可能
It's just not logistically possible.
是的  我們只是設定行為讓它們自己行動
No. We simply set the behaviour and leave them to it.
它們甚至自己建造蜂巢
They even construct these hives themselves.
它們繁殖
They reproduce...
-繁殖  -是的
- They reproduce? - Yes.
每個蜂巢都有個復制點
Each hive is a replication point.
-就像3D打印機  -沒錯
- It's like a 3D printer, basically. - Exactly.
它們創造自己的復制品
They create duplicates of themselves,
建造更多的蜂巢  以指數級擴張
create more hives and spread out exponentially.
-覆蓋全國  -也許你應該來這兒工作
- Cover the country. - Maybe you should work here.
是啊  我研究過這個
Yeah, well, I read up on it.
很了不起
It's impressive.
是啊
It is.
但要靠這種辦法真是遺憾
It's just a shame it's necessary.
沒有它們就會導致環境災難
The alternative would have been environmental catastrophe.
蜜蜂在滅亡
Bees were dying out.
所以  你們前來所為何事
So, what is it that brings you here?
我們認為你們的一只人造蜂
We think one of your ADIs
可能涉及一起不明死亡
may be involved in an unexplained death.
什么  死亡
Sorry? A death?
謝謝
Thank you.
第一時間下載無刪減美劇  必須登錄字幕組網站
沒錯  這是我們的
Yeah. It's one of ours.
但它們不是被設計來...
But, look, these are not designed to...
殺人  我也希望不是
Kill people? I'd hope not.
它會發生故障碼
Could it have malfunctioned somehow?
不會  它們發生故障的時候
No. I mean, when they do malfunction...
更好更快的原創翻譯 雙語字幕
有時會發生  但它們會直接壞掉
It happens, but then they just break,
掉到地上
they just hit the ground.
要是有人黑進去
What if someone hacked one
找到了控制它們的方式呢
and then they found a way of controlling it?
不可能
That's impossible.
它們的加密是軍用級別的
You see, it's got military-grade encryption,
你還需要一個診斷控制器
and you would need a diagnostic controller,
那也是加密的
which is also encrypted.
所以我看那種可能性...
So I would say the likelihood is--
我不懂他在說什么
I don't know what he's saying,
但聽起來并不是不可能
but it's not the same as "Impossible."
這是我們線上所有的蜂巢
This is every hive we have online.
看
See...
這幾個是這里的蜂巢
These are the hives in the building here.
每個蜂巢平均多少蜜蜂
How many bees per hive?
大約四千只
Around 4,000.
-就像空中管制  -沒錯
- It's like air traffic control. - Yeah.
那是搜索框嗎
Is that the search input?
是的  但是
Yeah, but, uh...
-抱歉  -你需要
- Sorry. - you'd need...
喬·鮑爾斯的郵編
Jo Powers' postcode.
是為了她嗎
Is that who this is about?
-你說會出現故障  -很少  沒錯
- You said you get some malfunctions? - A fair few, yes.
撞上車或是什么的  還有人捕捉它們
They smack into a car or something. We even had people trap them.
把它們放進微波爐里  拍視頻上傳
You know, put them in the microwave for YouTube videos.
這個會記錄所有掉線的人造蜂
And this logs any that drop off the system?
記錄一切  沒錯
Logs everything, yes.
你們星期一晚上在這附近有人造蜂掉線嗎
Did you lose any around here on Monday evening?
我可以查一下
Well, I can check.
只有一只  19:03時放出
Just one. Went out at 1903 hours.
我可以重放
Here, I can replay.
在那兒
There.
很奇怪
That's odd.
怎么奇怪了
What's odd?
它們進入新蜂巢時
When they pass between hives,
會進行管轄權交接
they switch from one jurisdiction to another.
這就像...
It's, you know, like a...
電話信號發射塔間的電話嗎
It's like a phone between cell masts?
沒錯  它正打算這么做
Exactly. It tried to do that,
但并沒有東西接收它
but there was nothing to switch to.
除非有人仿造了一個蜂巢
Unless someone spoofed a hive
他們用這個方法黑了你們的人造蜂
and then they've used that to commandeer your ADI.
不會  那還得需要診斷控制器
No, you would need a diagnostic controller to do that.
一個控制器的控制范圍是多大
What's the range on one of those?
可能有10到20米
10, 20 metres, perhaps.
這么說控制這個的人
So whoever was controlling
就在20米的范圍內
it would have to be no more than 20 metres away.
在房子外面
Outside the house.
是的  可能甚至坐在輛車里
Yeah. Sitting in a car, even.
你能查到這是誰干的嗎
Can you trace back who did this?
可以  已經開始查了
Yes. I-I'm already trying to do that.
知道嗎
You know what?
沒人旁觀的話會查得更快
It would be easier without an audience.
好
Okay.
你們倆交換下電話號碼  保持聯系
You two swap numbers, keep a line of communication.
如果必要的話  你能把整個系統關閉嗎
Can you shut the whole thing down if need be...
只是假設
Hypothetically speaking?
短暫的停工都會破壞生態系統
Even a short stoppage would damage the ecosystem,
我們需要得到環保局的批準
and we'd need approval from the Department of the Environment.
我們需要顆粒計劃中
We'll need a list of any
所有有權限進入系統的人員名單
Granular staff that had access to that system,
在職和已離職的都要
past or present.
有些是政府雇員
Some were government employees.
可以的話  用不一樣的字體把他們標出來
再見
Bye.
尼克  這是顆粒計劃的員工資料
Nick, that's a set of Granular personnel records.
找出任何有嫌疑的人
Root out anyone interesting.
可能不是一個人  可能是團伙作案
Maybe not just one. Could be a group involved.
-那個  -我們其實該把這個上報給國家犯罪局
- Listen. - Technically we should refer this up to the NCA,
但他們休想從我手里奪走這個案子
but there's no fucking way they're taking this off me.
國家犯罪局已經知道了
The NCA already knows about it.
什么
What?
卡琳·帕克總督察
DCI Karin Parke?
-是的  -肖恩·李  國家犯罪局
- Yes. - Shaun Li, National Crime Agency.
什么風把你給吹來了
How come you're here?
不止一起
There's been more than one.
這是塔斯克  昨晚的事
This is Tusk, last night.
-媽的  -他們本以為是痙攣
- Shit. - They thought it was a fit.
把他帶到醫院
Took him to the hospital.
為阻止他自殘  不得不給他打了麻醉
He had to be anaesthetised to stop him mutilating himself.
X光顯示
X-ray seemed to indicate
他大腦里有斑塊或是腫瘤
some kind of plaque or tumour in his brain
于是他們給他做了核磁共振
so they popped him in the MRI.
是啊
Yeah.
就是一個大磁鐵
Basically one big magnet.
把這個從他腦袋里拉了出來  從眼窩中
Tore it right out of his head, through the eye socket.
人造蜂也損壞了
Battered the ADI too.
你們的那只更為完整
Yours is more intact
我需要拿去作分析
so I'm gonna need it for analysis.
這是證據
It's evidence.
兩起案子就形成規律了
Two's a pattern.
那就不是故障了
It knocks any malfunction theory in the head.
兩名被害人有相似特征
And they're similar victims.
相似特征
Similar?
都是正在被網絡聲討的人
Both in the middle of online shit storms.
如果你想殺掉一個人
Well, if you wanna kill someone,
更簡單的方法數不勝數
there's a million easier ways to do it.
這種方法  你隔著條街就可以下手
Pull this off and you've done it from across the street.
不會留下指紋和DNA
No fingerprints, no DNA.
就好像把他們咒死了
It's like wishing them dead.
操
Fuck.
各位  快過來
Guys? Come here.
那么...
Okay, so, um...
喬·鮑爾斯和塔斯克
Jo Powers and Tusk,
兩人都在網上被人罵了很久
both were being kicked around the Internet for hours,
但在兩人的案子中  人們發照片時
but in both their cases, people were also tweeting their photos
還會加上這個標簽#去死
accompanied with this hashtag: #DeathTo.
塔斯克#去死
-就像那個老師一樣  -對
- Like our friend the teacher. - Right.
她不知道她最初是什么時候聽說的
She didn't know where she'd first heard of it,
但回溯一下
but trace it back,
這個標簽似乎是上周末才出現的
and it looks like the first real use of the hashtag was last weekend.
誰用的
By who?
看起來...
Looks like, um...
似乎是一批僵尸號發了同樣的推文
looks like identical tweets from a set of duplicate bot accounts.
是自動的
Automated.
就像垃圾郵件
It's like spam.
有人想推廣這個標簽
This is someone trying to seed the tag, you know?
傳出去  就像個誘餌
Get it out there. It's like bait.
有人想讓大家都開始用它
This is someone wanting people to pick up on it.
看看發推者的頭像
Check out the senders' avatar photos.
蜜蜂  見鬼
Bees. Shit.
好吧
Okay.
不止如此
There's more.
每條推文都附有一段說明視頻
So each tweet had a sort of instruction video attached to it.
后果游戲
看
There.
"后果游戲"
"Game of Consequences"?
像是一場不受歡迎度比賽
It's like an unpopularity contest.
選個你不喜歡的人
Pick someone you don't like
如果選他的人足夠多
and if enough other people choose the same name,
那他就成了目標
then that's who gets targeted.
看
Here, watch.
后果游戲
Game of Consequences.
#去死
-第一步  選擇目標  -天啊
- One, pick a target. - Oh, my God.
第二步  發布他們的名字和照片
Two, post their name and photo
加上標簽#去死
with #DeathTo.
不
No.
第三步  人氣最高的目標
Three, most popular target
會在每天晚五點后被除掉
will be eliminated after 5 p.m. each day.
第四步  游戲在午夜時重置
Four, game resets at midnight.
-不  -操
- Oh, no. - Fuck.
#去死
有人在操控公眾投票  除掉得票最高的人
Someone's holding a public ballot, bumping off the top person.
天啊  簡直瘋了
Jesus, it's just mad.
是啊  而且在蔓延
Yeah, and it's growing.
第一天  63人給喬·鮑爾斯加了這個標簽
Day one. 63 people used the hashtag on Jo Powers, okay?
第二天  223人給塔斯克加了這標簽
On day two, 223 used it on Tusk.
-現在還有誰在發標簽  -比之前多太多了
- Who's using it now? - There's-- there's loads more people.
有不少人給財相加了標簽
There's quite a few votes for the Chancellor.
是啊
Yeah.
但第一名
But at number one...
880人給克拉拉·米茲加了標簽
is 880 people using it on someone called Clara Meades.
-她是誰  -克拉拉·米茲
- Who's she? - Clara Meades.
好
Okay, um...
她似乎是參加了一個示威游行
it looks like she was at a demo,
她在戰爭紀念碑前拍了張自拍
and she took a selfie in front of a war memorial.
假裝沖上面尿尿
Pretending to piss on it.
干得好  克拉拉
Nice work, Clara.
投票快結束了
Yeah, it's getting near the end of the vote,
提到她的人數還在爆長
and her mentions are blowing up.
-塔斯克案還沒公開吧  -沒有
- Tusk isn't public knowledge yet? - Um, no.
人們不知道標簽真好用
So people can't know the hashtag works.
他們是想用它嚇唬她
They're using it to scare her.
對  但他們會害死她的
Yeah, but they're gonna get her killed.
我們得在五點前找到她
We need to get to her before five.
嗯  正在調出她的個人信息
Yeah. Pulling her citizens details.
你不應該有那個的權限
You're not supposed to have access to that.
我知道  我只想獲取她的位置
Yeah, I know. Just getting her location.
克拉拉·米茲
倫敦
找到了
There.
@克拉拉·米茲 你大限將至  會讓你措手不及  膽顫吧
史上最爛的垃圾  克拉拉·米茲#去死
太放肆  臭不要臉@克拉拉·米茲
克拉拉·米茲#去死
@克拉拉·米茲 什么鬼
他們為你的自由才犧牲
去你媽@克拉拉·米茲 講真  #滾粗
講真  有些人真該...
喂
Hello?
她在
Yeah, she is.
好  稍等別掛
All right, all right, hold on.
克拉拉
Clara!
警察  找你的
Police. For you.
他們怎么知道我電話的
How did they get my number?
-喂  -克拉拉·米茲
- Hello? - Clara Meades?
我是倫敦警局的卡琳·帕克總督察
This is DCI Karin Parke, Met Police.
抱歉用這種方式找到你
Sorry to track you down like this,
但我們認為你有危險
but we think you may be in danger.
抱歉  這是惡作劇嗎
Sorry, is this a joke?
因為我收到的這些消息可不好玩
Because all this stuff I'm getting is not funny.
不是惡作劇  待在原地  我們過去找你
I'm not joking. Stay where you are until we get there.
關好窗戶
And keep your windows closed.
我設置了警戒線
I'm setting up a perimeter.
打給拉斯姆斯  我們需要他的協助
Call Rasmus, we need him across this.
-拉斯姆斯  -你好  布藍
- Rasmus? - Hi, Blue.
我發了你一個郵編和我的位置
I'm sending you a postcode and my GPS.
你得監控這一地區
I need you to monitor the area.
追蹤我的位置  看是否有異常情況
Track my location and see if you get anything unusual,
是否有失靈的人造蜂
any rogue ADIs, yeah?
好的
Yeah, great, good.
如果他們故伎重施
Look, if they come back,
我應該能抓住他們
I think I can catch them.
我已經布下了陷阱
I have basically set a trap.
他們要是再這么做  我們能抓到他們
So if they-- if they try it again, we've got them.
-你是蝙蝠俠嗎  -這是新產品
- Are you Batman? - They only just rolled them out.
這能讓途中所有紅燈都變綠
This'll turn every red light between here and there to green.
我操  要是國家犯罪局要這么牛
Fuck me. If this is the NCA life,
我應該申請調職
I should apply for a transfer.
走吧
Let's go.
我們可以帶她去這里
We can take her here.
是給恐怖分子線人準備的安全屋
It's a safe house for terrorist informers usually.
沒看到目標
No target sighted.
這是警方行動
This is a police operation!
請所有人立即疏散
Everybody vacate their premises now.
請疏散...
Please leave...
檢測到入侵
-怎么了  -有人想入侵
- What's that? - Someone's trying to break in.
-拉斯姆斯  -我發現有人試圖入侵
- Rasmus? - I just picked up an attempted breach.
好  顆粒計劃那邊發現入侵
Okay. Granular, they've got a breach.
-一只人造蜂剛剛掉線了  -哪里
- One ADI just went offline. - Where?
-距你們800米  -在我們的警戒帶之外
- 800 metres from your location. - That's outside our cordon.
如果有人想讓人造蜂朝這邊飛
If someone's trying to pilot it this way,
他們一看到警察就會讓它調頭
they're gonna turn 'round the moment they see all these uniforms.
-克拉拉·米茲  -是我
- Clara Meades? - Yeah.
我是卡琳·帕克  你收拾行李了嗎
I'm Karin Parke. Did you pack a bag?
-收拾了  放在門邊  -好  走吧
- Yeah, it's by the door. - Right, let's go.
-拉斯姆斯追蹤到他們了嗎  -還沒
- Rasmus got a track on them? - Not yet.
追蹤中
只是以防萬一  住一晚而已
It's just precautionary, and it's only for one night.
我上報一下
Just gotta call in.
還沒
No, not yet.
希望永遠都別  顆粒計劃在查
Hopefully never. Granular are onto it.
明白
Understood.
肖恩說  曾有個線人在這兒住過
They housed a witness here for a while, Shaun said.
肯定有孩子
Must've had kids.
你有孩子嗎
Have you got kids?
-沒有  -沒有
- No. - No.
沒這個打算
No plans.
上樓吧
Up the stairs.
拉斯姆斯
Rasmus.
依然沒進展  我無法追蹤
Still nothing. I can't trace it.
至少還有間套房
At least there's an en-suite.
-什么都沒有  -對
- Is there nothing? - No.
干這事的人把蹤跡掩蓋得很好
Whoever it is, they've masked their path well.
但那不是...
But that's not--
-操  -怎么了
- Fuck. - What?
-我們失去了一個蜂巢  -什么意思
- We just lost a whole hive. - What does that mean?
里面滿是人造蜂
Packed full of ADIs.
全都失聯了
Lost them all too.
-不  拉斯姆斯  -有數千只
- No-- Rasmus? - There's thousands of them.
-在哪  -離你們很近
- Where? - It's close to your location.
拉斯姆斯  再說一遍
Rasmus, say that again.
布藍  布藍  離你們非常近
Blue? Blue. It's close... it's very close to you.
發短信  給我發短信
Text it. Text it to me.
拉斯姆斯  短信  操
Rasmus. Text it to-- Shit.
我能重新裝修嗎
Do I get to redecorate?
喂  喂
Hello. Hello.
不...
No...
他們控制了一切
They've got the whole thing.
我們不能控制了
We're not in control anymore.
-他們控制了一切  -你在干什么
- They've got the whole thing. - What are you doing?
修好它
Fix it!
-你修不好嗎  -閉嘴
- Can't you fix it? - Shut up!
拉斯姆斯·斯約博格  快跑
操
Shit.
我們得走了  快  快走
We need to go. Now. Now! Come on!
跑  跑  跑
Go. Go, go, go.
怎么回事
What's-- what's happening?
卡琳
Karin...
進去  快走
In there! Go!
-幫我堵住門縫  -這是怎么了
- Help me block the gap! - Tell me what's going on!
你們要嚇死我了
You're scaring the shit out of me!
操
Fuck!
換氣扇  換氣扇
The fan! The fan!
離我遠點
Get it away from me!
慢慢來
Take your time.
我見過那么多尸體
I'd seen so many bodies before.
在犯罪現場  在尸檢時
At crime scenes, in autopsies.
但我從沒見過人死的過程
But I'd never seen anyone die.
她就在我面前
And she was right there.
你能形容下你同事  科爾森小姐的反應嗎
And can you describe the reaction of your colleague, Miss Colson?
布藍很受打擊
Blue took it hard.
我會關停它
I'll shut it down.
我們原以為  附近有一個神秘人士
We thought this was one guy, some Mr. Mystery in the vicinity,
劫持并控制了一只人造蜂
hijacking one ADI and personally controlling it.
但剛剛有成百上千只
But there were thousands of them.
-所以不可能是一個人  -對
- So it can't be that, right? - No.
-一個人不能同時控制那么多蜜蜂  -對
- One person can't fly hundreds at once. - No.
不管是誰  他們控制了整個系統
Whoever this is, they're controlling the whole system.
你知道他們是從什么地方控制的嗎
Do you know where they're controlling it from?
不知道  哪都有可能
No. Could be anywhere.
你他媽得搞明白這件事
You need to fucking sort this out!
人造蜂怎么知道目標是誰
How do the ADIs know who to target?
可能跟你用的是一種方法  通過身份數據庫
Could've found Clara the same way you did, the identity database?
不  那只能找到大致區域
No. That just gives you the basic area.
當時我們也在房間里  但它們只叮她
We were in the room too, and they only went for her.
面部識別  肯定是面部識別
Facial recognition. It's got to be facial recognition.
也就是說視覺傳感器的信號
Which means the feed from their visual sensors,
也被入侵了
that's been accessed too.
-不可能  -這是唯一的解釋
- That's not possible. - It's the only explanation.
每只人造蜂和蜂巢
Now look, the visual feed
之間的視覺信號都是加密的
is secure between each ADI and the hive.
-是了吧  -不過
- There you go. - Although...
政府支持計劃的條件之一就是...
one of the government's conditions for backing the project...
好了  夠了
Okay. Enough.
我們得同意  在政府安全機構需要時
We had to consent to permitting government security services
給他們視覺信號
access to the visual feed at times of quote,
以"加強國家安全"
"Increased national security."
就我理解  幾乎就是隨時
Which is, as I understand it, pretty much all the time.
-我并不高興  -你們同意了
- I wasn't happy about it. - Your lot went along with it.
你們并沒有給我們多少選擇
What that implies a greater range of options than your lot presented.
-那他們的確在監視我們  -這都是機密
- So they are spying on us. - This is all classified.
那你做了什么
So what did you do,
給政府通信總部開了一道后門嗎
did you put in a back door and route it through GCHQ?
你能拿到監控  能控制交通燈
I mean, you do CCTV, you do traffic cams.
你還有什么事是沒插手的
So what don't you have your fucking noses in?
外面有幾百萬個這玩意到處飛
Look, millions of those things flying around,
支撐著我們的生態系統
propping up the ecosystem?
太好了  拯救地球  皆大歡喜
Well, that's great, save the planet, hallelujah!
政府不會因為某個實驗室人員的三言兩語
Government's not going to pump billions into it
和200張贊成票  就投上幾十億
just 'cause some lab coat says so, and it grabs 200 green votes.
他們看到了可利用的機會  就把握住了
They saw an opportunity to get more, they took it.
全國性監控
Total nationwide surveillance.
我們能連續數周以嫌犯根本想不到的方式追蹤他們
We tracked suspects for weeks in ways they couldn't dream of.
我們阻止爆炸  大規模槍殺
We prevented bombings, mass shootings.
通過監視大眾
By spying on the public.
并保證他們的安全  這才是他們想要的
And keeping them safe, which is what they want.
但是克拉拉·米茲并不安全  對嗎  肖恩
Clara Meades isn't safe, though, is she, Shaun?
你要是早告訴了我們  也許本可以幫上忙
Knowing what you knew, that might've helped us,
-但你沒有  你偏要保守你的秘密  -好了
- but no, you kept your little fucking secret. - Okay.
好了  政府是個混蛋
Okay! The government's a cunt.
這我們早就知道了
We knew that already.
克拉拉的事很快就會傳開
Word's going to get out about Clara.
人們一大早醒來
The public's going to wake up
就會得知這個瘋狂的暗殺游戲
and find this mental assassination game going on,
很快就會出現下一具尸體
and soon we're going to have another body.
-那我們怎么辦  -我不知道
- So what do we do? - I don't know.
我們完全被墻了  什么都看不到
We're totally locked out. Totally blind.
要是我能知道他們是怎么入侵的
If I can work out how they got in,
我也許能逆向工程
I might be able to reverse engineer
想辦法奪回控制權
some means of getting control back.
人造蜂有命令日志或面板緩存之類的東西嗎
Do the ADIs have a command log, on-board cache?
-有  但都是加密的  -我需要解碼密鑰
- Yeah, but that's encrypted. - I'll need the key to that.
我翻閱了員工檔案  發現幾個有嫌疑的人
Been through the employee files, found some POIs.
把他們帶來
Bring them in.
你要來嗎  訊問顆粒計劃的人
Are you sitting in on these? Granular interviews?
我有別的事
I've got to be somewhere.
現在是7點15
It's 7:15.
第四天
已經出現三起
Three deaths have now been
與社交網絡上一標簽有關的死亡事件
linked to a hashtag circulating on social media.
我操  #去死 這玩意是真的嗎
哈哈哈  第一個是皮克林  湯姆·皮克林#去死
別用那個標簽  變態
飽受爭議的記者喬·鮑爾斯
Controversial journalist Jo Powers...
查爾斯·澤因娜#去死
早上好  你發過那個標簽嗎
Good morning. Have you posted the hashtag?
這是真的還是都市傳說
Is it real or an urban myth?
#去死 是什么
已經有上千人參與標簽
Well, thousands have been taking part,
但是那些人真的罪該致死嗎
but how culpable are they?
有人在死去  我們想知道你的想法
People are dying, and we want to hear your thoughts.
#去死
8789條
維多利亞·斯凱爾蘭#去死
如果你發#去死  你手上沾有鮮血
湯姆·皮克林#去死
發送
七號線  萊娜
Line seven, Liana...
#去死  87000條
#不要用  34000條
#去死
這是真的在發生的事
This is real, this is happening...
評論
南希·梅
羅德·法林頓#去死
我就想看到她死
I am happy to see her die.
又不是那個標簽害死他們的
It's not the hashtag killing them.
評論  不要發
法林頓勛爵和所有戀童癖#去死
死亡標簽投票
那只是個游戲
That's just a game.
如果你是個混蛋  你活該被羞辱
Like, if you're an arsehole, you deserve to be shamed.
#去死
史蒂夫  五號線
Steve, line five.
但我想說  總有人會登上榜首
Yeah, but my point is, someone's gotta be top of the list, yeah?
羅德·法林頓#去死
#去死
那為什么不能是
So why not make it someone,
#去死
#去死  144000條
罪有應得的人呢  比如種族歧視者
you know, who deserves it, like a racist.
要是有人得在五點死  那不如是湯姆·皮克林#去死
趕緊除掉皮克林  湯姆·皮克林#去死
我看到被加這個標簽的有名人  政客
With the hashtag, I've seen celebrities, politicians,
這個標簽是真的嗎  #去死
好消息是我們能除掉財相了  湯姆·皮克林#去死
誰都有
everyone.
干掉那個混蛋皮克林  湯姆·皮克林#去死
但這不代表你要
This doesn't mean you have to
坐在這里鼓勵大家參與
sit there encouraging people to take part.
問題是  這件事已經發生了
The point is this is already happening.
人們知道他們都可以參與
And people know that they can jump onboard
因為誰都不會知道他們到底有沒有參與
because nobody will ever know if they did or didn't.
我們先停停  看看現在的前五名
Well, let's just pause for a moment and go back to that top five.
我們之前說過  財相排在第一位
As we have been saying, the Chancellor is at number one,
我希望大家好好想想
and I want us to think about that.
這說明全國上下的選擇是什么
What does that tell us about the choice of the nation?
班森·帕克·布朗  法林頓勛爵  夏洛特·沃克  詹姆斯  湯姆·皮克林
我對他占據榜首并不感到驚訝
Well, I can't say I'm surprised that he's number one on the list.
他早就很不受歡迎了
He's been pretty unpopular for quite a long time now.
但這代表他應該占據榜首嗎
But does that warrant his place on this list?
我是說  人們不需要想太多
I'm saying people don't have to think too hard about it.
現在他是第一位
Now that's he's number one,
這會引發更多討論  也許更多人會投票
that should generate more discussions and probably more votes.
正在連接人造蜂HV20101752
謝謝你抽時間來
Thanks for your time.
不是嗎
No good?
不是
No good.
-聽起來很精彩  -肖恩
- Well, that's all fascinating... - Shaun.
-但我們什么時候能關閉一切  -湯姆
- But when do we shut it down? - Tom.
請原諒我對你手下
Forgive me for being sceptical
能力有所質疑
about your agency's basic competence.
-湯姆  -我現在就是砧板上的肉
- Tom. - I'm on the fucking chopping block here.
名單第一位  都是人民選的
Number one on the list. The people's fucking choice!
法林頓才排第四  他是個戀童癖
Farrington's number four, and he's a paedophile.
-疑似戀童癖  -他就是  你心里清楚
- Suspected paedophile. - He did it. You know he did.
我們關掉一切社交網絡吧
Let's just shut it down. All social media.
整個該死的因特網  拔掉開關
The whole bloody Internet, pull the plug.
就今天
Just for today,
至少等這位拇指姑娘麻利行動起來
at least until Thumbelina here pulls his finger out
抓到幾個人再說
and he actually catches someone.
我不建議關閉一切
I wouldn't advise shutting things down.
-但還是可能做到的  -整個社交網絡
- But it's possible? We can do that? - The whole of social media?
-是啊  效仿朝鮮  -技術上來說可以
- Yeah. Pull a North Korea on it. - Well, yes, technically.
-好  那就關掉  -這不是個好主意
- Right, so push the off switch. - That's not a good idea.
-是嗎  -在我看來不是
- No? - Not in my opinion.
那好吧
Right, okay.
只不過作為目標人物  我表示異議
It's just that speaking as a marked man, I beg to fucking differ.
如果我們關掉  你還是第一位
If we shut it down, you'll still be number one.
事實上你肯定是第一了
Guaranteed to be, in fact.
他說得對  如果繼續開著  至少還有幾小時
He's right. If we let it run on, at least there's a few hours.
五點前什么都有可能  投票結果可能會變
Anything could happen before five o'clock. The vote might change.
也可能不會
Yeah, and it might not.
那則報道呢  檔案呢
What about that report? The archive job?
1985年  關于法林頓的備忘錄
From 1985, that memo about Farrington?
-那件事毫無關聯  -泄露出去
- That was over an unrelated matter. - Leak it.
湯姆  這是抹黑
Tom, that would be a smear.
就是徹頭徹尾的抹黑  就是這意思
A head-to-toe shit smear, I fucking hope so.
他八十多歲了  活夠了  讓他去死吧
He's in his 80s. He's had his life. Fuck him under the bus.
我能提一個備選方案嗎
If I could suggest an alternative?
我們把你轉移到一個安全的地方
We move you to a safe location.
在五點之前保護好你
Have you secured before five.
昨晚你們這樣做很有用嘛
Worked out well for you last night.
我展示給你看
I'll show you.
下一個是苔絲·沃倫德  她是實習的
This next one's Tess Wallender. She was a junior.
所以技術水平不高
So not much in the way of technical skills.
-因為個人原因退出顆粒計劃  -神經衰弱
- Quit Granular for personal reasons. - Nervous exhaustion, yeah.
辭職前在顆粒的人事部工作
Worked in Human Resources for Granular until she quit.
她在網上發布了一個家伙的照片  說他騷擾她
She took a photo of a guy on the Tube, said he'd harassed her,
發表下流的評論什么的
lewd comments or something.
后來發現他有學習障礙
Turned out he had a learning disability
所以她被罵得很慘  在...
so she caught a ton of shit on--
社交網絡上
On social media.
你好  我是卡琳·帕克總督察
Hello. I'm DCI Karin Parke.
修復面板緩存
感覺好像
It was like
突然遭遇了一場狂風暴雨
having a whole weather system turn against me.
一條接一條的辱罵留言
Just hate message after hate message,
不停地發過來
around the clock, all piling on.
難以形容這對我造成的影響
It's hard to describe what that does to your head.
突然間出現了幾百萬個隱形人
Suddenly there's a million invisible people,
都在談論他們怎么怎么鄙夷我
all talking about how they despise you.
簡直像一種精神疾病
It's like a mental illness.
操
Fuck.
怎么了
What?
該死
Shit.
我的確犯了個錯誤
I mean, hands up, I made a mistake,
但是最讓我難過的是人們開心地貶低我的樣子
but the way people enjoyed kicking me, that's what got to me.
他們因此產生的快感
The casual fun they had and, um...
我只是覺得我受不了了
I just felt I couldn't go on.
是誰發現到了你
Who found you?
加內特  我的室友
Garrett, my flatmate.
他在我割腕五分鐘后在浴缸里發現了我
He found me in the bath five minutes after I'd slashed them.
太瘋狂了
I mean, it's crazy.
我當時快迷糊了  他把我拖出浴缸
I'm half-conscious. He's dragging me out of the bath,
我要他出去  我說"我沒穿衣服"
and I'm telling him to get out, saying, "I'm naked."
他在我手腕上綁毛巾  讓我保持清醒
He tied towels 'round my wrists, kept me conscious,
不停撫摸我的頭發  和我說話
kept stroking my hair till the ambulance arrived,
直到救護車來
talking to me.
有點別扭
Sort of weird.
我覺得他一直對我有意思
I think he always had a thing for me.
我們也在同一個地方工作...很尷尬
And we worked at the same place so, you know... awkward.
-他在顆粒工作  -是的  研究人造蜂
- He worked at Granular? - Yeah. On the ADI thing.
他可是個神童
He was a real wunderkind.
-特別聰明  -你剛剛說他叫什么
- Ultra-smart. - What did you say his name was?
加內特  加內特·斯科爾斯
Garrett. Garrett Scholes.
加內特·斯科爾斯
Garrett Scholes.
我們要知道加內特在哪里...
We need the whereabouts of a Garrett--
斯科爾斯  我們剛要告訴你
Scholes. We were about to tell you.
這隱藏在喬·鮑爾斯體內人造蜂的面板緩存中
It was buried in the on-board memory of the Jo Powers' ADI.
-什么東西  -一份宣言  98頁的宣言
- What was? - A manifesto. A 98-page manifesto.
后果之齒
看看這個  還有自拍
And check this out. There's fucking selfies in it.
這不是表演
我們能行動了嗎
So we're good to go?
炸彈布置完畢
Okay, that's the charge in place.
好
Okay.
后退
Pull back.
準備完畢
We're all set here.
引爆
Detonate.
計劃是我們把你送到一處地堡
So, the plan is, we move you to an underground bunker,
炸掉方圓十里內所有的蜂巢
knock out every hive within a ten-mile radius.
然后呢  把我丟在那里  要多久
And, what, just leave me there? How long for?
這只是暫時的措施
It's a temporary measure.
處理掉所有蜂巢要多久
How long till you take out all the hives?
那大概有兩三萬個  起碼得要兩年
There's 20,000, 30,000 of them. That would take two years.
兩年  一天一名受害者
Two years, a victim a day.
更重要的是  環境的影響會...
More to the point, the environmental impact would--
去他媽的
Fuck that.
該死
Shit!
-怎么了  -操
- What? - Fuck!
后退  后退
Stay back, stay back!
后退
Get back!
快走  快走
Go, go, go! Get away!
上帝啊  快走
For fuck's sake, move!
你的后備計劃是什么
What's your Plan B?
后果之齒  加內特·斯科爾斯的宣言
他是最早的員工之一  但我們沒考慮他
He was on the original employee roster, but we discounted him.
他六個月前出國了
He left the country six months ago.
我以為我們要找的人就在附近
We thought we were looking for someone nearby.
追查他的行蹤  任何蛛絲馬跡都不要放過
Run a full trace on him. Everything we can find.
有創造力的瘋子  這是最糟糕的
Lunatic with production values, that's the worst kind.
"由于技術革命
"Thanks to the technological revolution,
我們能夠不計較后果地表達憤怒
we have the power to rage and accuse,
提出控訴  抨擊他人
spout bile without consequence.
只有被迫了解技術賜予我們的力量
Only by being forced to recognize the power technology grants us,
才能清楚個人責任..."
to acknowledge individual responsibility..."
都是這些東西嗎
Is it all like this?
他把人們類比為昆蟲  說我們喜歡殘酷
He likens the population to insects, says we revel in cruelty,
這是我們應該摒棄的弱點
that it's a weakness that should be bred out of us.
他重復表示
Recurrent theme is
要人們面對他們的言行舉止所帶來的后果
he wants people to face the consequences of what they say and do.
強迫他們面對
Wants to force that on them.
這整件事就是個道德教育嗎
The whole thing's a moral lesson?
他希望我們發現這個  并散播出去
He wanted us to find this and spread it about.
去他媽的
Well, fuck him.
尼克·謝爾頓
加內特·斯科爾斯#去死
這不是表演
我操
Fuck.
圖像提取
加內特·斯科爾斯#去死
發送
該死
Shit.
卡琳  卡琳  他搞砸了
Karin. Karin. He's messed up.
他親自拼湊了這些文件  對吧
He's put this document together himself, right?
作者姓名在元數據里
His author name's in the metadata.
但他把其他東西都抹去了
But he stripped out everything else,
所以我們不知道他是什么時候寫的
so we don't know when he's written it, for example.
大多數照片都是從網上截取的  除了這張
Most of the photos are clipart off the Internet, except this one.
-他的自拍  -這就是他搞砸的地方
- The selfie. - That's where he's screwed up.
他是用自己的手機拍的
He's taken it with his phone,
手機在圖像上留下了地理標記
and the phone left a geotag on the image.
-你知道他是在哪里拍的嗎  -知道
- So you know where he took this? - I know precisely where.
他在這里  顆粒總部在那里
He's here and Granular HQ is there.
尼克·謝爾頓  加內特·斯科爾斯#去死
-武裝警察  趴下  -武裝警察
- Armed police! Stay down! - Armed police!
-武裝警察  不許動  -武裝警察  出來
- Armed police! Stay where you are! - Armed police! Show yourselves!
過去
Move!
左邊
Left.
-安全  -安全
- Clear! - Clear!
安全
Clear!
過得像富翁和名流
Lifestyles of the rich and famous.
那里  鍛造爐
There. The forge.
漂亮
Nice one.
我在鑒證科檢查過的半數硬盤都被燒過
Half the drives I sifted in forensics had scorch marks on 'em.
-你怎么看  -看起來是他的工具包
- What do you think? - Yeah. Looks like his toolkit.
-能用嗎  -可以說是開啟大門的鑰匙
- You can use it? - Pretty much the key to the door.
你能奪回控制權嗎  發送失效指令
So you can get control back? Send the deactivation?
我拿到了他的源代碼
Well, I've got his source code.
-應該能把他弄出去  -快點
- I should be able to bounce him out. - Be quick.
開啟大門的鑰匙
Key to the door?
這人不像是會把"鑰匙"隨便亂丟的人
Our guy doesn't seem the type to leave keys lying around.
我進去了
Well, I'm in.
好  讓它失效
Okay. Deactivate her.
-我得先修復權限  -該死
- Yeah, I need to repair permissions. - Fucking hell.
奇怪
That's weird.
奇怪什么
What's weird?
-快沒時間了  -這份文件之前不在的
- Time's ticking. -That file. Wasn't there before.
-這份文件嗎  -對
- This file? - Yeah.
是什么
What is it?
-布藍  -我覺得是國際移動設備識別碼
- Blue? - I think they're IMEI numbers.
那是什么
What does that mean?
每部手機  每個設備都有一個獨特的號碼
Every phone, every device has a unique number,
也就是國際移動設備識別碼
an IMEI number.
與特定的用戶綁定在一起
It tethers it to a unique user.
-對  -但我能進行反向搜索
- Yeah. - But I can check, just... reverse lookup.
慢慢來
Take it easy.
這些人是誰
Who are these people?
我不知道  一共有38.7萬人
I don't know. There's 387,000 of them.
這些人是你那些間諜收集的嗎
Are these IDs your spooks have been collecting?
-不是  你準備好了嗎  -快了
- No! Are you ready yet? - Yeah, almost there.
慢著  慢著
Wait. Wait.
罵人蛋糕的那個老師叫什么名字
What was the name of that teacher? Hate cake.
-莉莎·巴哈  -莉莎·巴哈
- Liza. Liza Bahar. - Liza Bahar.
我的天
Fuck's sake.
這是所有使用過標簽的人的名單
This is a list of everyone who's used the hashtag.
什么
What?
所有參加過"后果游戲"的人
Everyone who took part in the Game of Consequences.
莉莎·巴哈
看來是通過政府通信總部得到了他們的身份信息
They've hoovered up their ID from GCHQ by the looks of it.
那個后門看來是雙向的
That backdoor worked both ways, it seems.
-看有沒有我  -什么
- See if I'm on there. - What?
我早些時候加標簽發了斯科爾斯的照片
I posted the tag earlier with Scholes' face.
只是想惹他不開心
Just trying to get a reaction from him.
嗯  快好了
Yeah, yeah, almost there.
嗯  你在上邊
Yeah, you're there.
尼克·謝爾頓
快好了
Almost there.
他為什么要收集參與人的名單  畢竟
Why has he collected everyone who took part? I mean...
好  準備好了
Okay. I'm ready.
關閉系統
-見鬼  -馬上關閉
- Shit. - Run it now.
不  想想  他留了線索給我們
No. Think. He left us a trail.
-得了吧  -帶地址信息的照片
- Oh, come on. - That photo with the whereabouts,
他不會犯這么大的錯誤
it's too big a mistake for him.
他早知道我們會這么做
He knew we'd do this.
現在我們要關閉系統了
Now we're shutting it down, all right?
這或許會引發終極事件
And maybe that'll trigger some endgame,
和名單有關的事件
something to do with that list.
萬一他們才是他真正的目標呢
What if those are his real targets?
名單上那些人
The people on the list.
所有參與其中的人
Everyone who took part.
承擔后果
Consequences.
仇恨對象只是誘餌
The hate figures were the bait.
玩家才是目標
The players are the target.
-確認關閉  -稍等一會兒  好嗎
- Run the deact command. - Now just wait a minute, okay?
關閉系統
-確認  -不行
- Run it. - No!
別...干什么
No... What?
指令已發送
正在處理
見鬼
Shit!
好了
Yeah.
好了  行了
Yeah, it worked.
-操  -抱歉  但必須這么做
- Fuck! - Sorry, but that needed doing.
-不  不  不  -怎么了
- No, no, no, no, no. - What?
不  不
No. No.
-操  -不
- Fuck! - No.
見鬼
Shit.
不
Oh, no.
看啊
There's...
很不幸
We're all tragically
我們都清楚那周接下來發生的事
familiar with the rest of the events of that week.
隨后的大規模死亡不需提醒
And we need no reminding of the sheer scale
大家也都記得
of the loss of life that followed.
對  忘不掉
No. No, we don't.
科爾森女士后來如何了
And what became of Ms. Colson?
我想她很自責
I think she blamed herself.
不對  我知道她自責
No. I know she did.
她覺得是因為自己順著他布的局走
She felt she'd followed his breadcrumb trail and
才觸發了整件事
sprung the whole thing.
她離開了警局
She left the force.
我再沒有她的消息
I didn't hear from her.
打電話  發郵件  都沒有回復
Rang her, tried E-mailing, but no response.
后來
Then, um...
大概四個月后
About four months later,
他們找到了她的東西
they found her things.
在一處海灘上
On a beach.
還有遺書
With a note.
她自殺了嗎
She killed herself?
是這么推測的  沒錯
That's the base theory, yes.
帕克女士  感謝你
Ms Parke, I would like to commend you
花時間出面提供證詞
for sharing your testimony and your time.
謝謝
Thank you.
我們要#真相
告訴我們真相
正義
先生
Señor.
-謝謝  -謝謝
- Gracias. - Gracias.
號碼不予顯示  一條新信息
找到他了
刪除